# **Crystal Fernandes**

Mumbai, India +91 7338233202 cryssie.fernandes4@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated java developer with 11+ years of experience in designing, developing and enhancing multiple software systems. Notable achievements include driving the delivery of API solutions for multiple requirements, reduction in delay of trade download via API from 3 hours to >2 minutes for high volume members where records downloaded can range from 10,000 to 100,000 per request, implementing and providing assistance for several software/infrastructure upgrades for various applications as well as handing the BAU of other smaller applications.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## NSE, NSEIT Ltd., Mumbai — Project Lead

January 2021 - Present

- Led the end to end development and deployment of APIs for eventual decommission of multiple legacy thick client applications. Interacting with members for feedback/concerns on the API and implementing changes that would be beneficial to them.
- Developed and deployed multiple spring boot components for segregation, allocation and monitoring of collateral at the client level via file upload, screen based or API.
- Oracle Weblogic server and Java version upgrade for multiple Connect2NSE applications.
- Implemented changes across multiple Connect2NSE applications for DR-45 switchover..
- Mentoring team members, assigning tasks, overseeing development and production releases, supervising and supplying knowledge and guidance as needed.
- SSL certificate renewal for UAT and Production nginx domain web servers as well as configuration of application endpoints and troubleshooting.
- Handled bug fixes, production releases and contingencies, UAT environment setup and availability and member queries for various Connect2NSE applications.
- In charge of creating and maintaining documentation for APIs.

## NSE, NSEIT Ltd., Mumbai — Module Lead

July 2018 - January 2021

- Successfully handled the decommission of legacy NOTIS thick client (exe) as well as enhancing the user experience and improving performance in multiple market segments in NOTIS API.
- Implemented changes in NOTIS application for Interoperability among exchanges (NSE, BSE and MSE).
- Developed and implemented Two Factor Authentication using an external SMS API and email based OTP for multiple Connect2NSE applications.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: Java 11, Java 8, Java 7, Java 6
- Frameworks/Technologies:
   Spring Boot, REST API,
   OAuth 2.0, J2EE, Servlets,
   JSP, Hibernate, Oracle
   Weblogic Server, Nginx,
   JPA, JSF, Angular 2
- Database: Oracle, MySQL, DB2
- Tools: Eclipse, SVN, Maven, GIT, ANT, Teamforge, JIRA, HP ALM, IDEA IntelliJ
- Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall

#### **EDUCATION**

BITS Pilani, Pilani, India — M.Tech. in Software Engineering

R.D. National & W.A. Science College, Mumbai, India — B.Sc. in Information Technology

2012

St. Andrew's College, Mumbai, India — H.S.C. - Science 2009

- Implementation of digital signing in the EFDR system using HSM for member banks thereby removing the dependency on physical token and hardware.
- Upgrade of linux UAT and production servers from RHEL 6.x to 8.3 version.
- Setup and support of testing environment provided for trading members to test end to end trade flow during the NSE mock sessions to integrate members' back office and NOTIS
- Developed the NOTIS API for the Capital Market segment.
- Actively provided support to other teams for implementation of Two Factor Authentication for their own applications.

## **Credit Suisse**, **Wipro Technologies**, Bangalore — *Senior* Project Engineer

Dec 2016 - May 2018

- Developed and enhanced the backend for the Bulk Action module using Angular 2 for the new Tax UI. Notable sub-tasks included creation of the service to retrieve data from the database and implementation of search/filter criteria for the page.
- Handled development and upkeep of multiple applications integral to Credit Suisse day-to-day operations in addition to maintaining Dispo as part of the Payments BAU team.
- Mentored junior engineers, actively provided guidance and oversaw their progress and work status spanning from solution design to code reviews and test case coverage.
- 2.5 years of extensive knowledge in the private banking domain dealing with SWIFT, SIC, SEPA, payment order types, cross border payments, payment processing and other banking related processes.

## **Credit Suisse**, **Wipro Technologies**, Bangalore — *Project* Engineer

June 2014 - Dec 2016

- Lead Developer of Dispo (Web application for Risk Assessment of payment orders). Responsibilities included driving enhancements to the application, starting from requirement analysis and feasibility to production deployment. Primary point of contact for client queries and post production support.
- Upgraded platforms of numerous core banking applications to improve performance and ease of maintenance.
- Migrated CORBA services to Web Services as part of
- organization wide reform of multiple banking systems. Responsible for enhancements to several Credit Suisse banking applications to ensure compliance with Industry standards.

# **Seagate**, **Wipro Technologies**, Bangalore — *Project* Engineer

Nov 2012 - June 2014

the eReturns System (Return Material Authorization System - RMA) to handle the return process for Seagate hard drives. The legacy RMA system was not capable of handling the volume and geographical diversity of returns. The eReturns System was designed to handle returns across multiple locations and streamlined the return process for users and affiliate partners.